International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE) Records
International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE) Records
1986-2006
International Society for Comparative Adult Education.
0.5 linear ft
Bulk consists of correspondence related to planning of annual meetings/conferences and challenges to "growing" the organization; there is also a small amount of material relating to the book Comparative Adult Education, published by ISCAE, and a few folders of conference material
2537567
Biographical History
The International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE) is a network of adult educators whose members come from more than 30 countries. The organization has its origins in 1960 in a working group put together by Dr. Alexander N. Charters and Roby Kidd that focused on international and comparative adult education. The organization was known as the Committee for Study and Research in Comparative Adult Education (CSRCA) until 1992, when it adopted its current name.
The network has no statutes and requires no accounting or membership fees; although it does publish occasional papers the primary venue for exchange of information is the conferences held annually in various locations.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE) Records consist of correspondence and conference materials.
Correspondence, much of which consists of printed emails. relates almost entirely to the planning of each year's conference. Topics touched on include researchers' work, developments affecting ISCAE, and promotions and challenges the organization faced along the way. There are also address lists, participant lists, drafts of registration forms, calls for papers, occasionally drafts of papers submitted, and other similar material.
Conference material contains material actually printed and produced for a given conference. These include programs, papers, and conference proceedings. Organizations represented, other than ISCAE itself, include the Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE) and UNESCO's Committee for Study and Research in Comparative Adult Education (CSRCAE).
Arrangement of the Collection
The bulk of the collection is correspondence, arranged in chronological order. Conference material is arranged alphabetically by the name of the sponsoring organization and then within that chronologically.
Related Material
has extensive holdings related to adult education. Please refer to for a complete list of manuscript collections, and search for cataloged print material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Boucouvalas, Marcie, 1947-; Charters, Alexander N.; Reischmann, Jost, 1943-; Titmus, Colin J.; Commission of Professors of Adult Education.; Committee for the Study and Research in Comparative Adult Education.; International Society for Comparative Adult Education.; Adult education -- Congresses.; Adult education -- Cross-cultural studies.; Adult education -- Research.; Comparative education.; Correspondence.; Conference proceedings.; Newsletters.; Adult education teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jost Reischmann, 2007-2008.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General, 1991 (Box 1)
  - General, 1992 (Box 1)
  - General, 1993; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1994 (Box 1)
  - General, 1995; includes one folder of papers, possibly submitted to or presented at that year's conference; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1996 (Box 1)
  - General, 1997 (Box 1)
  - General, 1998; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Book, Comparative Adult Education, 1998-1999; contributors to book published by ISCAE; includes a few corrections, discussion of final details (Box 2)
  - General, 2000 (Box 2)
  - General, 2001 (Box 2)
  - General, 2002 (Box 2)
  - General, 2003 (Box 2)
  - General, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
- Conference materials, papers, programs, etc.
  - Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE), 1986 (Box 2)
  - Committee for Study and Research in Comparative Adult Education (CSRCAE), 1991 (Box 2)
  - International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE), 1998; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - International Society for Comparative Adult Education (ISCAE), 2006 (Box 1)